They've killed the boy!
They've killed young Paolo!
They've killed your son Paolo!
Murderers! Murderers!
My son...
All my respect, Don Ciccio.
You killed my husband because
he wouldn't give in to you.
And his oldest son Paolo...
...because he swore revenge.
But Vito is only nine
and dumb-witted.
He never speaks.
It's not his words I'm afraid of.
He's weak. He couldn't hurt anyone.
But when he grows, he'll grow strong.
Don't worry. This little boy
can't do a thing to you.
When he's a man,
he'll come for revenge.
I beg you, Don Ciccio,
spare my only son.
He's all I have left.
I swear to God he'll never do
you any harm. Spare him!
Vito, run!
Move and I'll kill him!
Run, Vito!
Kill him!
Any family who hides the boy
Vito Andolini will regret it!
You understand?
Anybody who hides the boy
Vito Andolini is in for trouble!
Vito, we're praying for you!
If anyone is hiding the boy
Vito Andolini...
...turn him over to us.
Don Ciccio will thank you for it!
It'll be better for the boy,
and better for you!
Any family who hides the boy
Vito Andolini will regret it!
Nurse.
Money?
Interpreter!
Where are you from?
- What is your name?
- Maria.
What is your name?
Come on, son. What is your name?
Vito Andolini from Corleone.
Corleone. Vito Corleone.
Okay, over there.
Next.
Tell him he has smallpox.
Quarantine three months.
Vito Corleone!
Here he is. This is him.
Did you bring the car keys?
Laurie! Laurie!
Mama!
- Look who's here.
- Father Carmelo.
- This is Father Carmelo.
- I'm Merle Johnson.
Mama!
- Here I am.
- Constanzia, after one week?
I sent the car to the airport last week
to pick you up.
It was chaos. Anyway, here I am, just
one week late. This is for my mama!
- What is this?
- You remember Merle?
Hello. How are you? Thank you.
Where's Michael? I've got to talk to him
and I can't wait on line.
You go see your children first.
Then you worry about waiting on line to
see your brother. Like everybody else.
Ladies and gentlemen...
A most distinguished guest
would like to say a few words.
Please welcome Senator Pat Geary
of the State of Nevada.
And there is Mrs Geary.
Thank you very much.
This is a very, very happy day
for me and my wife Mrs Geary.
We see Nevada far too seldom.
But today we can join with old friends,
we can make new friends
and we help celebrate
a young man's first Communion.
And also to thank that boy's family for
a magnificent contribution to the State.
I have here in my hand a cheque
made out to the university
and it is a magnificent endowment
in the name of
Anthony Vito Corleone.
The cheque is signed by
that young man's parents
whom I think we should recognise.
Mike, Pat, Kay, stand up, please.
Let the folks see you!
Folks, I want you to join me
in giving a real Nevada thank you
to Mr and Mrs Michael Corleone!
We also have, as a special added
attraction, the Sierra Boys Choir
who have chosen a certain special song
and a special arrangement
to honour their host,
Mr Michael Corleone.
Boys.
The plaque.
Okay, fellows, did you get that one?
Okay, that's good.
Now, Senator,
just you and Mrs Corleone.
My lawyer Tom Hagen. Senator Geary.
He arranged everything
through your man Turnbull.
- Yes, yes.
- Sit down.
I thought that you and I
would talk alone.
I trust these men with my life, Senator.
To ask them to leave would be an insult.
Well, it's perfectly all right with me
but I am a blunt man and I intend
to speak very frankly to you.
Maybe more frankly
than anyone in my position
has ever talked to you before.
The Corleone family
has done well in Nevada.
You own, or control,
two major hotels in Vegas
and one in Reno.
The licences were grandfathered in
so there was no problem
with the Gaming Commission.
Now my sources tell me
that you plan to make a move
against the Tropigala.
They tell me that within a week,
you're going to move Klingman out.
Quite an expansion. However, it will
leave you with a little technical problem.
The licence will still be
in Klingman's name.
- Turnbull is a good man.
- Yeah, well, let's cut out the bullshit.
I don't want to spend
more time here than I have to.
You can have the licence.
The price is 250,000 dollars.
Plus five per cent of the gross monthly
of all four hotels, Mr Corleone.
The price for the licence
is less than 20,000 dollars, right?
That's right.
- Why would I pay more than that?
- Because I intend to squeeze you.
I don't like your kind of people.
I don't like to see you come out
to this clean country in oily hair
dressed up in those silk suits
and try to pass yourselves off
as decent Americans.
I'll do business with you, but the fact is
that I despise your masquerade,
the dishonest way you pose yourself
and your whole fucking family.
Senator,
we're both part of the same hypocrisy.
But never think it applies to my family.
All right, all right.
Some people have to play little games.
You play yours.
Let's say that you'll pay me
because it's in your interest.
I want your answer and the money
by noon tomorrow. One more thing.
Don't you contact me again, ever.
From now on you deal with Turnbull.
Open that door, son.
Senator, you can have
my answer now if you like.
My offer is this...
Nothing.
Not even the fee for the gaming licence,
which I would like you to put up.
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
Ladies! I didn't know you were out here.
- Honey, we have to go.
- Really? I'm sorry.
- It's been delightful.
- It was our pleasure.
It was wonderful talking to you.
Fredo! Fredo, you son-of-a-bitch,
you look great!
Frank Pentangeli!
I thought you was
never coming out west, you big bum!
I've got to check on my boys.
- What's with the food here?
- What's the matter?
A kid gives me a Ritz cracker
with chopped liver and says, "canapés".
I said, "Can of peas, my ass. That's
a Ritz cracker and chopped liver!"
Bring out the peppers and sardines!
Seeing you reminds me of New York
in the old days!
You remember Willi Cicci, who was
with old man Clemenza in Brooklyn?
We were all upset about that.
Heart attack, huh?
No, that was no heart attack.
That's what I'm here to see
your brother Mike about.
- But what's with him?
- What do you mean?
Do I have to get a letter of introduction
to get a sit-down?
- You can't get in to see Mike?
- He's got me waiting in a lobby!
- Johnny Ola.
- Al Neri.
- Do you know my lawyer Tom Hagen?
- I remember Tom from the old days.
Rocco.
- What's this?
- It's an orange from Miami.
Take care of Johnny's men.
They look like they might be hungry.
Johnny?
Tom won't stay. He only handles
specific areas of the business.
Sure, Mike.
- What are you drinking, Johnny?
- Anisette.
- If you need anything, I'll be outside.
- Just tell Rocco we're waiting, Tom.
- I just left Mr Roth in Miami.
- How is his health?
It's not good.
Can I do anything or send anything?
He appreciates your concern, Michael,
and your respect.
That casino...
Registered owners. Jacob Lawrence,
Allan Barclay. Beverly Hills attorneys.
The real owners are
the old Lakeville Road group
and our friend in Miami.
Klingman runs it and owns a piece of
it too, but I've been instructed to tell you
that if you move him out,
our friend in Miami will go along.
It's very kind of him.
Tell him it's greatly appreciated.
Hyman Roth always makes money
for his partners.
One by one, our old friends are gone.
Death, natural or not,
prison, deported...
Only Hyman Roth is left, because he
always made money for his partners.
I can't believe it! Out of 30 professional
musicians there isn't one Italian!
Let's have a tarantella!
You! Up, up, up!
Questa mano!
What the hell have we here?
- I'll see my sister alone.
- It concerns me too. May I stay?
How are you, honey? You've met
Merle, he was with me in Vegas.
- I saw him with you.
- Could I have a drink?
Al, please get him a drink!
We're going to Europe. I'd like to book
passage on The Queen.
Why don't you go to a travel agent?
We're getting married first.
The ink on your divorce isn't dry yet,
and you're getting married?
You see your children on weekends.
Your oldest boy was picked up in Reno
for a theft you don't even know about.
You fly around the world
with men who use you like a whore!
- You're not my father!
- So why come to me?
I need money.
Connie, Connie, Connie...
I want to be reasonable with you.
Why don't you stay with the family?
You can live on the estate
with your kids.
You won't be deprived of anything.
I don't know this Merle. I don't know
what he does or what he lives on.
Tell him marriage is out of the question
and you don't want to see him any more.
He'll understand, believe me.
Connie.
If you don't listen to me
and marry this man,
you'll disappoint me.
- Famiglia!
- Cent'anni!
What's "Chen dannay"?
"Cent' anni". It means 100 years.
It means we should all live happily
for 100 years. The family.
- It would be true if my father were alive.
- Connie.
Hey...
Merle, you've met my sister-in-law,
Deanna.
- Fredo's wife.
- My pleasure.
With all respect, I didn't
come here to eat dinner!
I know, I know.
- I just want to dance!
- You're falling all over the floor.
You're just jealous
because he's a real man!
- I'm going to belt you right in the teeth.
- You couldn't belt your mama!
These Dagos are crazy
when it comes to their wives.
Michael says that if you can't
take care of this, I have to.
- I think you'd better.
- Never marry a Wop.
They treat their wives like shit!
I didn't mean to say Wop. Don't!
What are you doing to me,
you big slob? Help!
Fredo!
- I can't control her, Mikey.
- You're my brother, don't apologise.
Clemenza promised the Rosato
brothers three territories after he died.
You took over and didn't give it to them.
I welched.
Clemenza promised them lu cazzo.
He promised them nothing.
- He hated them more than I do.
- Frankie, they feel cheated.
You're sitting up in the Sierra Mountains
and you're drinking...
- What's he drinking?
- Champagne.
Champagne cocktails, and passing
judgement on how I run my family.
Your family's still called Corleone.
And you'll run it like a Corleone.
My family doesn't eat here,
doesn't eat in Las Vegas...
...and doesn't eat in Miami...
...with Hyman Roth!
You're a good old man and I like you.
You were loyal to my father for years.
The Rosato brothers
are taking hostages.
They spit right in my face, all because
they're backed up by that Jew in Miami.
I know. That's why
I don't want them touched.
- Not touched?
- No, I want you to be fair with them.
You want me to be fair with them?
How can you be fair to animals?
Tom, listen. They recruit spics,
they recruit niggers.
They do violence in their grandmothers'
neighbourhoods!
And everything with them is whores!
And junk, dope!
And they leave the gambling to last.
I want to run my family without you
on my back. I want those Rosatos dead!
- No.
- Morte.
I have business that's important with
Hyman Roth. I don't want it disturbed.
Then you give your loyalty to a Jew
before your own blood.
You know my father did business
with Hyman Roth. He respected him.
Your father did business with
Hyman Roth, he respected Hyman Roth,
but he never trusted Hyman Roth
or his Sicilian messenger boy,
Johnny Ola.
You'll have to excuse me. I'm tired,
and I'm a little drunk!
I want everybody here to know, there's
not going to be no trouble from me!
Don Corleone.
Cicci, the door...
You want him to leave now?
Let him go back to New York.
I've already made my plans.
The old man had too much wine.
It's late.
How's the baby?
- Sleeping inside me.
- Does it feel like a boy?
Yes, it does, Michael.
Kay?
I'm sorry about all the people today.
Bad timing.
It couldn't be helped, though.
It made me think
of what you once told me.
"In five years the Corleone family
will be completely legitimate."
That was seven years ago.
I know. I'm trying, darling.
Did you see this?
Why are the drapes open?
Kay, are you all right?
- Are you hit?
- No.
It's all right.
Stop! Stop!
Halt!
They're still on the property.
Please stay inside.
- Keep them alive.
- We'll try.
Alive!
Stay by the door.
Yeah, come in.
- Mike, are you all right?
- Yeah.
There's a lot I can't tell you, Tom.
And I know that's upset you in the past.
You felt it was because of
some lack of trust or confidence.
But it's because I admire you
and love you
that I kept things secret from you.
Now you're the only one I can trust.
Fredo?
Well, he's got a good heart.
But he's weak and he's stupid,
and this is life and death.
Tom, you're my brother.
I always wanted to be thought of as
a brother by you, Mikey. A real brother.
I know that.
You're going to take over.
You're going to be the Don.
If what I think has happened,
has happened, I'm leaving here tonight.
I give you complete power. Over Fredo
and his men. Rocco, Neri, everyone.
I'm trusting you
with the lives of my wife
and my children,
the future of this family.
- If we catch them, will we find out...
- We won't catch them.
Unless I'm very wrong,
they're dead already.
They were killed by somebody
close to us.
Inside. Very, very frightened
that they botched it.
You don't think that Rocco and Neri
had something to do with this?
See... All our people are businessmen.
Their loyalty is based on that.
One thing I learnt from Pop
was to try to think
as people around you think.
On that basis, anything is possible.
Mike, they're dead!
Right outside my window!
I want to get out of here.
They're lying there dead!
Over here! There's two of them.
Looks like they were hired
out of New York. I don't recognise them.
Won't get anything out of them now.
Fish them out.
Get rid of the bodies.
- Where's Mike?
- Rocco.
Anthony, everything is going to be
all right. Try to sleep.
- Did you like your party?
- I got lots of presents.
I know. Did you like them?
Yeah. I didn't know the people
who gave them to me.
Well, they were friends.
- Did you see my present for you?
- It was on my pillow.
I'm going to be leaving
very early tomorrow.
- Will you take me?
- No, I can't, Anthony.
- Why do you have to go?
- I have to do business.
I could help you.
I know. Some day you will.
Get some sleep.
She's really beautiful.
You've got to see her.
Wait till you see her.
Words can't describe her.
I left Naples. I left Mama.
For a no-good tramp!
Now here I am in America,
in New York.
Alone! Thinking of my mother.
Without news from home.
Finally, a letter from Naples!
Vito, how do you like my little angel?
Isn't she beautiful?
She's very beautiful.
To you, she's beautiful. For me,
there's only my wife and son.
Our dear mother...
...is dead!
We'll go backstage later
and take her to eat.
Sit down, you bum!
Oh, excuse me, Don Fanucci.
We'll go see her backstage.
Who was that?
The Black Hand.
That's Fanucci... the Black Hand.
We'll talk about it tomorrow.
Tomorrow! Always tomorrow!
You'll pay me today!
Let's go.
Not my daughter! Let her go!
Here, take all my money!
Vito, come on.
I know what you're thinking. But
you don't know how things are.
Fanucci's with the Black Hand.
The whole neighbourhood pays him.
Even my father, in the grocery store.
If he's Italian...
...why does he bother other Italians?
He knows they have nobody
to protect them.
Forget that. Did you like my angel?
If you're happy, I'm happy.
Don't you feel well?
Is your boss treating you all right?
Forget it.
Hey, you speak Italian?
Hide this for me!
Next week I'll come and get it!
Abbandando, meet my nephew!
How's business?
It's good, it's good.
Fanucci's mad. Says the
neighbourhood's getting sloppy.
People don't pay on time,
don't pay the full amount.
Says he's been too nice to everyone.
So Fanucci's changing?
Sure. He wants double
from everybody.
Even from my father.
I'm a friend, right? So you'll
let him work here?
I've got some bad news.
I feel rotten about telling you this...
But Fanucci... he's got a nephew...
And you have to give him my job.
You've always been good to me,
ever since I came here.
You looked after me like a father.
I thank you.
And I won't forget it.
Vito!
Oh, no!
Take this to your family.
Thanks anyway. But please,
I can't accept.
What a nice pear!
I'm Clemenza, you still
have my goods?
Did you look inside?
I'm not interested in things
that don't concern me.
A friend of mine has a nice rug.
Maybe your wife would like it.
Sure she would. But who has
money for a rug?
It would be a present.
I know how to return a favour.
Yeah, sure.
My wife would like it.
That son of a bitch! He isn't home!
Damn, he didn't even leave the key.
Well, he won't mind.
Come on in.
Hey, Vito, come on in!
This is your friend's place?
This is a real palace.
One of the best.
Vito, give me a hand, will you?
Look how pretty it is, Santino!
Come on in.
It's all right. Hyman's in there.
- Would you like a tuna sandwich?
- No, thank you.
...pick up of two by Holden.
Second and eight for S. C...
- Mr Roth?
- Come in, Michael.
Sit down, make yourself comfortable.
It's almost over.
- Do you follow the football game?
- Not for a while I haven't.
I enjoy watching football
in the afternoon.
One of the things I love
about this country. Baseball too.
Ever since Arnold Rothstein
fixed the World Series in 1919.
I heard you had some trouble.
Stupid.
People behaving like that with guns.
The important thing is you're all right.
Good health is the most important thing.
More than success, more than money.
More than power.
I came here because
there's going to be more bloodshed.
I wanted you to know,
so another war won't start.
Nobody wants another war.
Frank Pentangeli asked my permission
to get rid of the Rosato brothers.
When I refused he tried to have me
killed. He was stupid, I was lucky.
I'll visit him soon.
The important thing is that nothing
interferes with our plans for the future.
Nothing is more important.
- You're a wise and considerate man.
- And you're a great man, Mr Roth.
- There's much I can learn from you.
- Whatever I can do to help, Michael.
- Excuse me. Lunch.
- Come in.
- Thank you, my dear.
- You're going to break your eardrums.
- Enjoy it.
- Thank you.
You're young, I'm old and sick.
What we'll do in the next few months
will make history.
It's never been done before.
Not even your father would dream
that such a thing could be possible.
Frank Pentangeli is a dead man.
You don't object?
He's small potatoes.
What's up?
We got company?
What's going on?
Michael Corleone is here.
Where is he?
He's in your den. You better hurry.
He's been waiting a half hour.
Is something wrong?
I wish you would have let me know
you were coming.
- I could have prepared something.
- I didn't want you to know.
- You heard what happened?
- I almost died. We were so relieved...
In my home!
In my bedroom where my wife sleeps!
Where my children come to play.
In my home.
I want you to help me take my revenge.
Michael, anything. What can I do?
Settle these troubles
with the Rosato brothers.
I don't understand. I don't...
I don't have your brain for big deals.
But this is a street thing.
That Hyman Roth in Miami.
He's backing up those sons-of-a-bitches.
- I know he is.
- So why ask me to lay down to them?
It was Hyman Roth
that tried to have me killed.
I know it was him.
Jesus Christ, Mike.
Jesus Christ, let's get them all.
Now while we've got the muscle.
This used to be my father's old study.
It's changed.
I remember there used to be
a big desk here.
I remember when I was a kid. We had
to be quiet when we played near here.
I was very happy that this house
never went to strangers.
First Clemenza took it over. Now you.
My father taught me many things here.
He taught me in this room.
He taught me, "Keep your friends close,
but your enemies closer."
If Hyman Roth sees that I interceded
in this, in the Rosato brothers' favour,
he'll think his relationship with me
is still good.
That's what I want him to think.
I want him relaxed and confident
in our friendship.
Then I'll be able to find out
who the traitor in my family was.
- Yeah?
- Fredo, this is Johnny Ola.
- We need some more help.
- Johnny?
Jesus Christ, what the hell time is it?
- Who's that, honey?
- Listen good, Fredo.
Why are you calling me?
I don't want to talk to you.
Pentangeli is going to accept
the Rosato brothers' deal.
- Oh, God.
- Will he come alone?
I don't know. You've got me in
deep enough already.
Everything will be all right. Pentangeli
says he's willing to make a deal.
All we want to know is if he's on
the level, or if he'll bring his boys.
You lied to me. I don't want you
to call me any more.
- Your brother won't find out we talked.
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- Who was that?
- Wrong number.
- Frankie, I've got nobody here.
- Wait in the car, Cicc'.
- Frankie.
- That's okay, Cicc'.
- What's this?
- A lucky C note for our new deal.
Ritchie. Give us a taste.
We were all real happy
about your decision, Frankie.
- You won't regret it.
- I don't like the C note, Rosato.
I take that as an insult.
Michael Corleone says hello!
Close the door!
Your friend the cop...
Hey, Ritch. It's dark in here.
Are you open or closed?
I just came in to clean up a little,
you know?
What's the matter?
- Is that something on the floor?
- Carmine, not here!
Anthony!
You open this bar
and I'll blow your head in!
Freddy, it's good to see you.
- How is he?
- He's okay. He's in the back.
Girls, take a hike.
In this room here.
- I want to talk to him alone first.
- Come on.
I thought I could help you, Senator.
Hagen?
- Listen, I did not...
- It's all right.
- I didn't do anything.
- It's okay. You're very lucky.
My brother Fredo operates this place.
He was called before anyone.
Had this happened some place else,
we couldn't have helped you.
When I woke up, I was on the floor.
- And I don't know how it happened.
- You can't remember?
I passed out.
Just a game. Jesus.
Jesus, Jesus!
Jesus God!
God!
I don't know, and I don't understand
why I can't remember.
Doesn't matter, just do as I say.
Put in a call to your office.
Explain that you'll be there tomorrow.
You decided to spend the night at
Michael Corleone's house in Tahoe.
- As his guest.
- I do remember that she was laughing.
We'd done it before, and I know
that I could not have hurt that girl.
This girl has no family.
Nobody knows that she worked here.
It'll be as though she never existed.
All that's left is our friendship.
- Yes?
- Sorry, but we're not to let you through.
- I’m just going to the market.
- We'll pick up anything you want.
- Whose orders are these?
- Mr Hagen's. He's coming.
I'll speak to him.
I wanted to explain,
but I had business in Carson City.
It's Michael's request for your safety.
We'll get anything you need.
- So I'm supposed to stay in my house?
- No, within the compound will be fine.
- We were going to New England.
- That's off.
- Am I a prisoner?
- That's not the way we look at it, Kay.
Come on, kids.
We're going back to the house.
Joe.
Cuba, Cuba!
Most respected gentlemen.
Welcome to Havana.
I want to thank this distinguished group
of American industrialists
for continuing to work with Cuba
for the greatest period of prosperity
in her entire history.
Mr William Shaw,
representing
the General Fruit Company.
Messrs. Corngold and Dant,
of United Telephone
and Telegraph Company.
Mr Petty,
Regional Vice President of
the Pan American Mining Corporation.
Mr Robert Allen
of South American Sugar.
Mr Michael Corleone of Nevada,
representing our associates
in tourism and leisure activities.
And my old friend and associate
from Florida,
Mr Hyman Roth.
I would like to thank United Telephone
and Telegraph for their Christmas gift.
A solid gold telephone.
Perhaps you gentlemen
would like to look at it.
- Mr President?
- Yes?
Could you discuss the rebel activity and
what this can mean to our businesses?
- Of course.
- Heavy stuff.
I assure you that, although the rebels
have started a campaign in Las Villas,
my staff indicates, with assurance,
that we'll drive them out of Santa Clara
before the New Year.
I want to put you all at ease.
We will tolerate no guerrillas
in the casinos or the swimming pools.
He said that they're making an arrest,
and in a few minutes
he'll let us through.
Johnny...
It's nothing.
Just some lousy bandits.
The police are cleaning them up.
Viva Fidel!
I hope my age is correct.
I'm always accurate about my age.
Make sure that everybody
sees the cake before we cut it.
I'm very pleased
you're all able to come from
such distances to be with me today.
When a man comes
to this point in his life,
he wants to turn over
the things he's been blessed with.
Turn them over to friends,
as a reward for the friends he's had
and to make sure that everything
goes well after he's gone.
- Not for years.
- Hear, hear!
We'll see. The doctors would disagree,
but what do they know?
These are wonderful things
that we've achieved in Havana
and there's no limit
to where we can go from here.
This kind of government knows
how to help business, to encourage it.
The hotels here are bigger
and swankier
than any of the joints in Vegas.
We can thank our friends
in the Cuban government
which has put up half the cash with the
Teamsters, on a dollar for dollar basis
and has relaxed restrictions on imports.
What I'm saying is that we have now
what we have always needed...
Real partnership with a government.
Smaller piece.
You all know Michael Corleone
and we all remember his father.
At the time of my retirement, or death,
I turn over all my interests
in the Havana operation to his control.
But, all of you will share.
The Nacionale will go
to the Lakeville Road Boys,
the Capri to the Corleone family,
the Sevilla Biltmore also,
but Eddie Levine will bring in the
Pennino brothers,
Dino and Eddie, for a piece
and to handle the casino operations.
We've saved a piece
for some friends in Nevada
to make sure that things go smoothly
back home.
I want all of you to enjoy your cake.
So, enjoy!
- Happy birthday!
- L'chaim!
I saw an interesting thing happen today.
A rebel was being arrested
by the military police.
Rather than be taken alive, he exploded
a grenade he had in his jacket.
He killed himself and took a captain
of the command with him.
- Those rebels are lunatics.
- Maybe so.
But it occurred to me, that the soldiers
are paid to fight, the rebels aren't.
- What does that tell you?
- They can win.
This country has had rebels
for 50 years. It's in their blood.
I know, I've been coming here
since the Twenties.
We were running molasses
from Havana when you were a baby.
The trucks were owned by your father.
Michael.
I'd rather we talked about this
when we're alone.
The two million never got to the island.
It mustn't be known
that you held back the money
because you worried about the rebels.
Sit down, Michael. Sit down.
If I could only live to see it,
to be there with you.
What I wouldn't give for 20 more years.
Here we are, protected. Free to make
our profits without Kefauver,
the goddamn Justice Department
and the FBI.
90 miles away, in partnership
with a friendly government.
90 miles. It's nothing.
Just one small step for a man looking
to be President of the United States
and having the cash
to make it possible.
Michael,
we're bigger than U.S. Steel.
Mikey, how are you? Okay?
- Hi! Freddy Corleone.
- Mio frati.
Jesus Christ, what a trip!
I thought, "What if somebody knows
what I've got in here".
Can you imagine that? Two million
dollars on the seat next to me.
- Excuse me.
- It's okay.
You want to count it?
What's going on? I'm totally in the dark.
The family is making an investment in
Havana. This is a gift for the President.
That's great! Havana's great.
It's my kind of town.
- Anybody I know in Havana?
- Don't know. Hyman Roth, Johnny Ola?
No. I've never met them.
Listen, Mikey, I'm kind of...
Kind of nervous from the trip.
Can I get a drink or something?
I thought maybe we'd go out together.
I know a place where
we can spend some time together.
Sometimes I think I should have
married a woman like you did. Like Kay.
Have kids. Have a family.
For once in my life, be more like
Pop.
It's not easy to be a son, Fredo.
It's not easy.
Mama used to say,
"You don't belong to me."
"You were left on the doorstep
by gypsies."
Sometimes I think it's true.
You're no gypsy, Fredo.
Mikey, I was mad at you.
Why didn't we spend time
like this before?
You want a drink, right? Waiter!
Por favour...
- How do you say Banana Daiquiri?
- Banana Daiquiri.
- That's it?
- That's it.
Uno Banana Daiquiri
and a club soda.
Senator Geary flies in from Washington
tomorrow
with some government people.
I want you to show them
a good time in Havana.
- That's my speciality, right?
- Can I trust you with something?
Of course, Mike.
Later in the evening we're all invited
to the Presidential Palace
to bring in the New Year.
After it's over they'll take me home
in a military car, alone.
For my protection.
Before I reach my hotel,
I'll be assassinated.
- Who?
- Roth.
It was Roth who tried to kill me
in my home.
It was Roth all along.
He acts like I'm his son, his successor.
But he thinks he'll live forever
and wants me out.
- How can I help?
- Just go along, as if you know nothing.
- I've already made my move.
- What move?
Hyman Roth won't see the New Year.
You're to take it easy,
he'll be back tomorrow.
Fly in my own doctor from Miami.
I don't trust a doctor
who can't speak English.
- Gracias, señor.
- Buenas noches.
- Honey, go to the casino.
- If you're feeling better.
Feel fine.
- Play the bingo game.
- Okay. Nice to see you, Mr Paul.
My sixth sense tells me Fredo brought
a bag full of money. Where is it?
- You're pulling out?
- Just want to... Just want to wait.
- How do you feel?
- Terrible.
I'd give four million to be able to take
a painless piss.
- Who had Frank Pentangeli killed?
- The Rosato brothers.
I know, but who gave the go-ahead?
I know I didn't.
There was this kid I grew up with.
He was younger than me.
Sort of looked up to me, you know.
We did our first work together.
Worked our way out of the street.
Things were good.
During prohibition
we ran molasses into Canada.
Made a fortune. Your father, too.
As much as anyone,
I loved him and trusted him.
Later on he had an idea to build a city
out of a desert stop-over
for G.I.'s on the way to the West Coast.
That kid's name was Moe Greene
and the city he invented was Las Vegas.
This was a great man.
A man of vision and guts.
And there isn't even a plaque,
signpost or statue of him in that town.
Someone put a bullet through his eye.
No one knows who gave the order.
When I heard it, I wasn't angry.
I knew Moe, I knew he was headstrong.
Talking loud, saying stupid things.
So when he turned up dead, I let it go.
And I said to myself,
"This is the business we've chosen."
I didn't ask
who gave the order, because it had
nothing to do with business.
That two million in a bag in your room...
I'm going in to take a nap.
When I wake, if the money
is on the table, I know I have a partner.
If it isn't, I know I don't.
Does everybody know everybody?
You know Senator Geary.
Good to see you, Mike.
I'm glad we spend this time together.
Senator Payton from Florida...
Judge DeMalco from New York...
Senator Ream from Maryland...
Fred Corngold from UTT.
- That Fred does a mean cha-cha-cha!
- He does?
Gentlemen, it's refill time!
You might try some of the local drinks.
Cuba Libre, Piña Colada...
I think I'll try
one of those redheaded Yolandas.
- That you got! Con gusto...
- Johnny!
You don't know my brother Fredo.
Johnny Ola, Fredo.
- We never met. Johnny Ola.
- Pleasure.
Gentlemen, to a night in Havana!
- Happy New Year!
- Feliz Año Nuevo!
- Happy New Year.
- Hey, Freddy, why are we standing?
- Everybody stands.
- It's worth it. You won't believe this.
- I don't believe it already.
- 50 dollars, right?
- You've got a bet, mister.
That's Superman.
Did I tell you or did I tell you?
- I don't believe it!
- It's got to be fake.
It's real. That's why
he's called Superman.
Hey, Freddy, where did you find
this place?
Johnny Ola brought me here. I didn't
believe it, but seeing is believing!
- I see it, but still don't believe it!
- 50 bucks, Pat.
Roth won't go here,
but Johnny knows these places!
- Watch, he'll break a cracker with it.
- I want to see him break a brick!
Relax, we're taking you to the hospital.
...and you'll continue to get those.
I don't believe that President
Eisenhower would ever pull out of Cuba
as we have over one billion dollars
invested in this country.
The American public
believe in non-intervention...
Fredo! Where are you going?
I'm getting a real drink,
because I can't...
What kept Mr Roth?
I understood he was coming.
Reeves, what's the protocol?
How long should we stay?
I think a half hour ought to do it. Just
long enough to bring in the New Year.
It's New Year's Eve. Come on,
just for a minute.
There's a plane waiting to take us
to Miami in an hour.
Don't make a big thing about it.
I know it was you, Fredo.
You broke my heart.
You broke my heart!
Due to serious setbacks to our
troops in Guantanamo and Santiago...
...my position in Cuba is untenable.
I am resigning from office
to avoid further bloodshed.
And I shall leave the city immediately.
I wish all of you good luck.
Salud!
Viva la revolución! Viva Fidel!
Fredo!
Come on. Come with me.
It's the only way out of here tonight.
Roth is dead.
Fredo, come with me!
You're still my brother.
Fredo!
I'm Pat Geary, United States Senator.
Fidel! Fidel! Fidel!
Al. Get me a wet towel.
Does Kay know I'm back?
My boy? Did you get him
something for Christmas?
- I took care of it.
- What was it, so I'll know.
It was a little car with an electric motor
that he can ride in. It's nice.
Thank you, Al.
Fellows, could you step outside
for a minute?
Where's my brother?
Roth got out on a private boat.
He's in a hospital in Miami.
He had a stroke, but recovered okay.
Your bodyguard is dead.
I asked about Fredo.
I think he got out.
He must be somewhere in New York.
All right.
I want you to get in touch with him.
I know he's scared.
Tell him everything is all right.
Tell him I know Roth misled him. That
he didn't know they would try to kill me.
- They can come in now.
- There was something else.
What?
What? Come on.
Kay had a miscarriage.
- Was it a boy?
- At three and a half months...
Can't you give me a straight answer?
Was it a boy?
I really don't know.
Poor little Fredo, he's got pneumonia.
Young man, I hear you and
your friends are stealing goods.
But you don't even send a
dress to my house. No respect!
You know I've got three daughters.
This is my neighbourhood.
You and your friends should
show me some respect.
You should let me wet
my beak a little.
I hear you and your friends
cleared $600 each.
Give me $200 each, for your own
protection. And I'll forget the insult.
You young punks have to learn
to respect a man like me!
Otherwise the cops will
come to your house.
And your family will be ruined.
Of course if I'm wrong about how much
you stole - I'll take a little less.
And by less, I only mean -
a hundred bucks less.
Now don't refuse me.
Understand, paisan?
I understand.
My friends and I share all the money.
So first, I have to talk to them.
Tell your friends I don't want a lot.
Just enough to wet my beak.
Don't be afraid to tell them!
600 bucks...
Suppose we don't pay?
You know his gang, Tessio.
Real animals.
Maranzalla himself let Fanucci
work this neighbourhood.
He's got connections with the cops, too.
We have to pay him.
$200 each... everybody agreed?
Why do we have to pay him?
Vito, leave this to us.
He's one person, we're three.
He's got guns, we've got guns.
Why should we give him the
money we sweated for?
This is his neighbourhood!
I know two bookies who don't give
anything to Fanucci.
Who?
Joe The Greek and Frank Pignattaro.
They don't pay Fanucci.
If they don't pay Fanucci, then
somebody else collects for Maranzalla!
We'll all be better off if we
pay him. Don't worry.
Now what I say stays in this room.
If you both like, why not give me
$50 each to pay Fanucci?
I guarantee he'll accept
what I give him.
If Fanucci says $200...
...he means it, Vito!
I'll reason with him.
Leave everything to me.
I'll take care of everything.
I never lie to my friends.
Tomorrow you both go talk to Fanucci.
He'll ask for the money.
Tell him you'll pay whatever
he wants. Don't argue with him.
Then I'll go and get him to agree.
Don't argue with him, since
he's so tough.
How can you get him to take less?
That's my business.
Just remember that I did you a favour.
Is it a deal?
Yes.
His family's out of the house.
Fanucci's alone in the cafe.
Vito, here's my 50 dollars.
Buona fortuna.
Are you sure he's going to go for it?
I'll make an offer he don't refuse.
Don't worry.
It looks like there's
$100 under my hat.
I was right.
Only $100...
I'm short of money right now.
I've been out of work... so just
give me a little time.
You understand, don't you?
You've got balls, young man!
How come I never heard
of you before?
You've got a lot of guts.
I'll find you some work
for good money.
No hard feelings, right? If I can
help you, let me know.
You've done well for yourself.
Enjoy the festa!
Oh, this is too violent for me!
What've you got there?
Michael, your father loves you
very much.
Mr Cicci, from the year 1942
to the present time,
you were an employee
of the Genco Olive Oil Company?
That's right.
But in actuality you were a member
of the Corleone crime organisation.
No, we called it
the Corleone family, Senator.
What was your position?
At first, like everybody else,
I was a soldier.
- What is that?
- A button, you know, Senator.
No, I don't know. Tell me.
When the boss says "push a button" on
a guy, I push a button. See, Senator?
Mr Questadt.
- You mean you kill people?
- What?
You kill people at
the behest of your superiors.
Yeah, that's right.
And the head of your family
is Michael Corleone?
Yeah, Counsellor. Michael Corleone.
Did you ever get such an order
directly from Michael Corleone?
No, I never talked to him.
Mr Cicci, could you amplify
your answer a bit?
- Do what?
- Could you expand on your answer?
I'm particularly interested in knowing,
was there always a buffer involved?
Someone in between you
and your superiors who gave the order.
Right, a buffer.
The family had a lot of buffers!
You may find this very amusing, but
the members of this committee do not.
Tell me something, Ma.
What did Papa think...
deep in his heart?
He was being strong...
Strong for his family.
But by being strong for his family...
...could he...
...lose it?
You're thinking about your wife...
about the baby you lost.
But you and your wife can
always have another baby.
No, I meant... lose his family.
But you can never lose your family.
Times are changing.
It's my pleasure.
I don't want money.
Take it as a gift.
If there's something I can do for you,
you come, we talk.
Signora Colombo, why did you
come to see me?
Your wife told me to ask
if you could help me.
She's in bad trouble.
Her neighbours complained to the
landlord about her dog.
He told her to get rid of the animal.
But her little boy loves that dog.
So she hid it.
When the landlord found out, he
got mad and told her to leave.
Now she can't stay even if she
gets rid of it.
I'm so ashamed!
He said he'd get the police to
throw us out on the street.
I'm sorry, but...
I could give you a couple dollars
to help you move.
I can't move!
I want you to talk to him!
Tell him I want to stay here!
What's your landlord's name?
His name is Signor Roberto.
He lives on Fourth Street, near here.
They break the windows,
they dirty the floors...
A real pig-sty, eh?
My name is Vito Corleone.
Signora Colombo is a friend of my wife.
She says she's been evicted
for no good reason.
She's a poor widow, she has nobody
to take care of her.
She has no relatives, no money.
All she has is this neighbourhood.
I already rented the place
to another family.
I told her that I'd talk to you.
That you're a reasonable man.
She got rid of the animal that
caused all the trouble.
So let her stay.
Impossible.
Are you Sicilian?
No, I'm Calabrese.
We're practically paisan,
do me this favour.
I already rented it!
I'll look like an idiot.
Besides, the new tenants
pay more rent.
How much more a month?
Five bucks.
Here's six months increase in advance.
But don't tell her about it.
She's very proud.
Come see me in another six months.
Of course, the dog stays. Right?
The dog stays.
Who the hell are you
to come give me orders?
Watch out or I'll kick your Sicilian ass
right into the street!
Do me this favour.
I won't forget it.
Ask your friends in the
neighbourhood about me.
They'll tell you I know how
to return a favour.
What a character!
That landlord is here... Roberto,
the one who owns those ratholes.
He's been asking all around
the neighbourhood about you.
I hope I'm not disturbing you,
Don Vito.
What can I do for you, Don Roberto?
What a misunderstanding! Holy Mary!
Of course Signora Colombo can stay!
I'm giving back the money you gave me.
Un, due, three, four, five, six, tutt'!
Because after all, Don Vito,
money isn't everything.
Can I sit down?
Your kindness to that widow
made me ashamed of myself.
The rent stays like before!
I'll even lower it.
I'll lower it $5.
I'll lower it $10!
Can I offer you some coffee?
I'm late for an appointment! I can't
this time! Ask me another time!
You'll have to excuse me for now.
I wish I could stay longer!
Just call me and I'll be here!
He won't be back. He'll hide out
in the Bronx!
- Vito, what do you think?
- We'll make a big business!
- New York City.
- Would you speak up, please?
New York City.
- Are you the son of Vito Corleone?
- Yes, I am.
- Where was he born?
- Corleone, Sicily.
Did he at times use an alias that was
known in certain circles as Godfather?
Godfather is a term used by his friends.
One of affection and respect.
Mr Chairman, I would like to verify
the witness'statement.
For years many of my constituents
have been of Italian descent.
I've come to know them well.
They have honoured me
with their support and their friendship.
I can proudly say that some of my
very best friends are Italian-Americans.
However, Mr Chairman, unfortunately
I have to leave these proceedings
in order to preside over a very important
meeting of my own committee.
Before I leave, I do want to say this,
that these hearings on the Mafia
are in no way whatsoever
a slur upon the great Italian people.
I can state from my own knowledge
and experience
that Italian-Americans are among
the most loyal, most law-abiding,
patriotic, hard-working
American citizens in this land.
It would be a shame, Mr Chairman,
if we allowed a few rotten apples
to give a bad name to the whole barrel.
Because from the time of Christopher
Columbus to the time of Enrico Fermi
to the present day,
Italian-Americans have been pioneers
in building and defending our nation.
They are the salt of the earth, and
one of the backbones of this country.
I'm sure we all agree
with our esteemed colleague.
Mr Corleone, you have been advised
as to your legal rights.
We have testimony from
a previous witness, one Willi Cicci.
He stated that you are head of the most
powerful Mafia family in the country.
- Are you?
- No, I'm not.
He testified that you are
personally responsible
for the murder of a New York
police captain in 1947
and with him a man
named Virgil Sollozzo.
- Do you deny this?
- Yes, I do.
Is it true that in the year 1950
you devised the murder of the heads
of "the Five Families" in New York
to assume and consolidate
your nefarious power?
- It's a complete falsehood.
- Mr Questadt.
Is it true you have a controlling interest
in three major hotels in Las Vegas?
No, it's not true. I own some stock in
some of the hotels there, but very little.
I also have stock in IBM and IT& T.
Do you have any control over gambling
and narcotics in New York State?
No, I do not.
Senator, my client
would like to read a statement.
Mr Chairman, I think this statement
is totally out of order at this time.
Sir, my client has answered this
committee's questions with sincerity.
He hasn't taken the Fifth Amendment,
so this statement should be heard!
No, I'll allow Mr Corleone to read
his statement. I'll put it in the record.
In the hopes of clearing
my family name
to give my children their share
of the American way of life
without a blemish on their name
and background,
I have appeared before this committee
and given it all my cooperation.
I consider it a great personal dishonour
to have to deny that I am a criminal.
I wish to have the following noted
for the record...
That I served my country faithfully
in World War Two
and was awarded the Navy Cross
for actions in defence of my country.
That I have never been arrested
or indicted for any crime.
That no proof linking me to any
criminal conspiracy
whether it is called Mafia
or Cosa Nostra or any other name
has ever been made public.
I have not taken refuge
behind the Fifth Amendment,
although it's my right to do so.
I challenge this committee to produce
any witness or evidence against me
and if they do not, I hope they will have
the decency to clear my name
with the same publicity
with which they have besmirched it.
I'm sure we’re impressed. Particularly
with your love for our country.
We'll be in recess
until 10:00 a.m. Monday
when we will produce a witness who'll
corroborate the charges against you.
At which time you may very well
be subject to indictment for per jury.
I remind you that you’re still
under subpoena. Adjourned!
Ten-to-one shot, you said.
A ten-to-one shot
he would take the Fifth, and I'd lose!
You sound like my bookie.
I owe that monkey my life.
- Well, just get a good night's sleep.
- Yeah.
You've got a big day tomorrow.
I've got you a new suit,
new shirt, new tie.
I'll shave you myself in the morning.
You'll look respectable for 50 million
of your fellow Americans.
Tomorrow... My life won't be worth
a nickel after tomorrow.
Come on! I saw this 19 times.
You've got a great home here,
for the rest of your life.
Nobody gets near you,
you're not going anywhere.
That's great. Beautiful.
Some deal I made.
You'll live like a king. You'll be a hero.
You'll live better here
than most people outside.
Some deal!
Alive. Pentangeli is alive.
- How did they get their hands on him?
- Roth. He engineered it, Michael.
When Frankie went to make a deal with
the Rosato brothers
they tried to kill him.
He thought you double-crossed him.
Our people with the detectives
said he was half dead, scared
and shouted that you'd turned on him.
They already had him on possession,
bookmaking, murder one and more.
The FBI has him airtight.
He's on an army base, 24 hour guards.
We can't get to him. You've opened
yourself to five counts of perjury.
What about Fredo?
What does he know?
He says he doesn't know anything,
and I believe him.
Roth, he played this one beautifully.
I'm going to talk to Fredo.
I haven't got a lot to say, Mike.
We have time.
I was kept pretty much in the dark.
I didn't know all that much.
What about now? Is there anything
you can help me out with?
Anything you can tell me now?
They've got Pentangeli.
I didn't know
it was going to be a hit, Mike.
I swear to God I didn't know.
Johnny Ola bumped into me
in Beverly Hills.
He said that he wanted to talk.
He said that you and Roth
were in on a big deal together.
And that there was something in it
for me if I could help him out.
He said that you were being tough
on the negotiations
but if they could get a little help
and close the deal fast,
it would be good for the family.
And you believed that story?
You believed that?
He said there was something in it
for me, on my own!
- I've always taken care of you, Fredo.
- Taken care of me?
You're my kid brother!
You take care of me?
Did you ever think about that?
Did you ever once think about that?
"Send Fredo off to do this,
send Fredo off to do that!"
"Let Fredo take care of some
Mickey Mouse nightclub somewhere."
"Let Fredo fetch somebody
at the airport!"
I'm your older brother,
but was stepped over!
- It's the way Pop wanted it.
- It's not the way I wanted it!
I can handle things, I'm smart!
Not like everybody says.
Like dumb. I'm smart
and I want respect!
Is there anything you can tell me about
this investigation? Anything more?
The Senate lawyer, Questadt.
He belongs to Roth.
Fredo,
you're nothing to me now.
Not a brother, not a friend.
I don't want to know you,
or what you do.
I don't want to see you at the hotels.
I don't want you near my house.
When you see our mother, I want
to know in advance, so I won't be there.
You understand?
Mikey.
I don't want anything to happen to him
while my mother's alive.
There's more people
than at a ballgame in here.
- Hey, there's Willi Cicci!
- Frankie Five-Angels...
This committee will come to order!
- State your name, please.
- Frank Pentangeli.
- Where were you born?
- Partinico, it's outside of Palermo.
Where do you live now?
I live in an army barracks
with the FBI guys.
We have here a witness
that will further testify
to Michael Corleone's rule of a criminal
empire that controls all gambling.
This witness has had no buffer
between himself and Michael Corleone.
He can corroborate enough charges
for us to recommend a charge
of per jury against Michael Corleone.
- Senator.
- Thank you, Chairman.
Mr Pentangeli.
Mr Pentangeli. Were you a member
of the Corleone family?
Did you serve under Caporegime,
Peter Clemenza,
and under Vito Corleone,
also known as the Godfather?
I never knew any Godfather.
I have my own family.
Mr Pentangeli, you...
You are contradicting
your own sworn statement.
I ask you again, sir,
here and now under oath...
were you at any time a member of
a crime organisation
led by Michael Corleone?
I don't know nothing about that!
I was in the olive oil business
with his father
but that was a long time ago.
We have a sworn affidavit.
Your sworn affidavit, that you murdered
on the orders of Michael Corleone.
Do you deny this confession, and do
you realise what will happen if you do?
The FBI guys promised me a deal
so I made up a lot of stuff about
Michael Corleone, just to please them.
But it was all lies. Everything!
They kept saying,
"Michael Corleone did this"
and "Michael Corleone did that".
So I said, "Yeah, sure. Why not?"
Mr Corleone, would you kindly identify
the gentleman sitting to your left?
I can answer that.
His name is Vincenzo Pentangeli.
- Is he related to the witness?
- He is, I believe, his brother.
- Will he come forward and be sworn?
- He doesn't understand English.
He came at his own expense
to aid his brother.
He's not under subpoena
and has an impeccable reputation.
- He knows nothing about this?
- To my knowledge, nothing.
I'm going to find out what happened!
This committee is now adjourned.
- The witness is excused.
- Senator!
Senator! This committee
owes an apology!
This committee owes an apology.
Apology, Senator!
- Michael, excuse me.
- Hello, darling.
The children are outside. We're going.
What do you mean?
We're leaving tomorrow.
Rocco?
I'll be in my room, Mike.
Michael, I'm not going back to Nevada.
I brought the children
to say goodbye to you.
I'm very happy for you.
I always knew you were too smart
to let any of them beat you.
- Why don't you sit down?
- No, I'm not going to stay long.
There are some things
I'd like to talk to you about.
Things that have been on my mind,
changes I want to make.
I think it's too late for changes, Michael.
- I wasn't going to say anything...
- What do you mean, "too late"?
What really happened with Pentangeli?
- His brother came and helped him.
- I didn't even know he had a brother.
Where is he now?
He's on a plane, back to Sicily.
All he had to do was show his face.
It was between the brothers, Kay.
I had nothing to do with it.
I don't want you going!
Not you, not the kids. No.
You're my wife and my children.
I love you and won't allow it.
You say you love me,
but talk about allowing me to leave!
Things between men and women
will not change.
You've become blind!
Look what's happened to us.
- Look what's happened to our son!
- Nothing's happened to him. He's fine!
- Anthony is not fine!
- I don't want to hear about it.
- Anthony is...
- I don't want to hear about it!
Over!
At this moment
I feel no love for you at all.
I never thought that would ever happen,
but it has.
Kay...
We're leaving tomorrow.
Why don't you take the kids
back to their room?
- Michael, you haven't heard me.
- Kay, what do you want from me?
Do you expect me to let you go,
to let you take my children from me?
Don't you know me? Don't you know
that that's an impossibility?
That I'd use all my power
to keep that from happening?
Don't you know that?
Kay...
In time, you'll feel differently.
You'll be glad I stopped you now.
I know that.
I know you blame me
for losing the baby.
Yes.
I know what that meant to you.
I'll make it up to you, Kay.
I swear I'll make it up to you. I'll...
I'm going to change.
I'll change. I've learnt that I have
the strength to change.
Then you'll forget about
this miscarriage
and we'll have another child.
And we'll go on, you and I.
- We'll go on.
- Oh, Michael!
Michael, you are blind.
It wasn't a miscarriage.
It was an abortion.
An abortion, Michael.
Just like our marriage is an abortion.
Something that's unholy and evil!
I didn't want your son, Michael!
I wouldn't bring another one
of your sons into this world!
It was an abortion, Michael.
It was a son and I had it killed
because this must all end!
I know now that it's over. I knew it then.
There would be no way, Michael,
no way you could ever forgive me.
Not with this Sicilian thing
that's been going on for 2,000...
- You won't take my children.
- I will.
- You won't take my children!
- They're my children too.
Fredo, give this to Grandmother.
Don Ciccio, it's Tommasino.
Allow me the honour of
introducing someone.
My partner in America, in New York.
His name is Vito Corleone.
We'll send him olive oil from here.
To his company in America.
They're olive oil importers, Don Ciccio.
We'd like your blessing, and your
permission to start work.
Where is this young man
from New York?
Have him come closer.
I can't see him so good.
My respects, Don Ciccio.
Give me your blessing.
Bless you!
What's your name?
You took the name of this town!
And what's your father's name?
His name was... Antonio Andolini.
Louder, I don't hear so good.
My father's name was
Antonio Andolini...
...and this is for you!
Michael, say goodbye.
Hi, Al.
Can I speak with you
for a second, Tom?
Tom, where's Mike?
Waiting for you to leave.
- Can I talk with him?
- Sorry, Fredo. No chance.
- Can I see him?
- He's in the boathouse.
Michael, it's Connie.
Michael...
I'd like to stay close to home now,
if it's all right.
Is Kay coming?
No.
Fredo's in the house with Mama.
He asked for you
and Tom said you wouldn't see him.
That's right.
Kids, why don't you go outside
for a while?
Please, I want to talk to you.
Michael, I hated you for so many years.
I think I did things to myself,
to hurt myself, so that you'd know
that I could hurt you.
You were just being strong for all of us,
the way Papa was.
And I forgive you.
Can't you forgive Fredo?
He's so sweet,
and helpless without you.
You need me.
I want to take care of you now.
Connie.
Tom, sit down.
Our friend and business partner,
Hyman Roth, is in the news.
- Did you hear about it?
- I hear that he's in Israel.
The High Court in Israel
turned down his request to live there.
His passport's been invalidated,
except to return here.
He landed in Buenos Aires yesterday.
He offered them a million dollars
if they'd let him live there.
- They turned him down.
- He's going to try Panama.
Panama won't take him.
Not for a million, not for ten million.
His condition is reported as terminal.
He's only got six months left.
He's had the same heart attack
for 20 years.
- That plane goes to Miami.
- That's right. That's where I want it met.
Impossible. They'll turn him over to the
Internal Revenue, Customs and FBI.
It's not impossible.
Nothing's impossible.
It would be
like trying to kill the President.
- There's no way we can get to him!
- Tom, you surprise me.
If anything in this life is certain,
if history has taught us anything,
it's that you can kill anyone.
- Rocco?
- Difficult. Not impossible.
Good.
Why did you ask me if something
was wrong when I came in?
I thought you were going to tell me that
you were moving your family to Vegas
and that you'd been offered the Vice
Presidency of the Houstan hotels there.
- I thought you'd tell me that.
- Must I tell you every offer I turn down?
- Let's do business.
- All right.
Just consider this, Michael.
Just consider it.
Roth and the Rosatos are on the run.
Are they worth it,
are they strong enough?
Is it worth it? You've won.
Do you want to wipe everybody out?
I don't feel I have to wipe everybody
out, Tom. Just my enemies, that's all.
Are you with me in these things,
or what?
Because if not, you can take your wife,
your family and your mistress
and move them all to Las Vegas.
Why do you hurt me, Michael? I've
always been loyal to you. What is this?
So... you're staying?
Yes, I'm staying.
What do you want me to do?
Hey, Anthony.
How would you like it if I taught you
how to catch the really big fish?
- Would you like that?
- Okay.
You know, when I was your age,
I went out fishing with all my brothers
and my father. Everybody.
I was the only one that caught a fish.
Nobody else could catch one.
Do you know how I did it?
Every time I put the line in the water
I said a Hail Mary
and every time I said a Hail Mary,
I caught a fish.
Do you believe that? It's true.
That's the secret.
- Do you want to try it out on the lake?
- Okay.
What else have you got?
Everything will be okay.
- Did my brother go back?
- Yeah, don't worry.
He's ten times tougher than me,
my brother. He's old-fashioned.
He didn't want dinner,
just wanted to go home.
That's my brother! Nothing could get
him away from that two-mule town.
He could have been big here.
He could have had his own family.
Tom,
what do I do now?
Frankie.
You were always interested
in politics and history.
I remember you talking about Hitler
back in '33.
Yeah, I still read a lot.
I get good stuff in there.
You were around the old-timers, who
built the organisation of the families,
basing them on the old Roman legions,
with "regimes," "capos" and "soldiers".
- And it worked.
- Yeah, it worked.
Those were the great old days,
you know.
We was like the Roman Empire.
The Corleone family
was like the Roman Empire.
Yeah,
it was once.
Frankie.
When a plot
against the Emperor failed
the plotters were always
given a chance
to let their families keep their fortunes.
Right?
Only the rich guys.
The little guys got knocked off and all
their estates went to the Emperors.
Unless they went home and killed
themselves, then nothing happened.
And their families were taken care of.
That was a good break, a nice deal.
Yeah.
They went home
and sat in a hot bath
opened up their veins
and bled to death.
And sometimes they had a little party
before they did it.
Don't worry about anything,
Frankie Five-Angels.
Thanks, Tom. Thanks.
- See you, Tom.
- Addio, Frankie.
Kay. You have to go.
- So pretty...
- Kay, please hurry. He's coming.
Anthony. Kiss Mama goodbye.
Anthony, kiss your mother goodbye!
Anthony, say goodbye to Mama.
Anthony. I love you, Anthony.
Kay, please.
All right.
Mary, come here.
Anthony.
Anthony, please. Kiss me once.
Easy.
Anthony! Anthony!
- He's here, we're going fishing.
- No!
Michael wants to take him to Reno now.
Shit!
Okay, kid, you have to go to Reno
with your pop.
- I'll take you fishing tomorrow, okay?
- Okay.
Hey, Anthony.
Listen, I'll catch one for you in secret.
Let's go.
- Mr Roth, I must take you into custody.
- I understand.
What's your reaction
to the Israeli High Court ruling?
I'm a retired investor on a pension.
I went to Israel to live there as a Jew,
in the twilight of my life.
Hey, Frankie! Come on out,
let's play some Hearts.
Frankie!
Is it true you're worth
over 300 million dollars?
I'm a retired investor,
living on a pension.
I came home to vote
in the presidential election
because they wouldn't give me
an absentee ballot.
Jesus Christ.
Hail Mary, full of grace.
The Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women.
Blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners.
Hey! Everybody, pay attention.
This is my friend Carlo Rizzi.
- You know my brother Fredo.
- Sure.
This is my stepbrother Tom,
and that's his girl Theresa.
This cute little thing is my sister Connie.
Say hello to Carlo.
He's good-looking, isn't he?
Yes.
The droopy thing is Mike.
We call him Joe College.
Sit down. Talk to each other.
Hey, Mr Einstein...
- The cake.
- Sally, get in here!
- I was scared.
- Come on.
- Where's your father?
- Christmas shopping.
Let's see that thing.
That's nice!
- Should I put the candles on now?
- Yeah. You help her, Carlo.
- What is that? Rum?
- Yeah.
Don't touch the antipasto
until Pop sees it.
He's not ugly...
What do you think of the nerve of those
Japs? Bombing us on Pop's birthday.
They didn't know it was Pop's birthday.
Not surprising after the oil embargo.
They've got no right dropping bombs!
Are you a Jap-lover?
- 30,000 enlisted this morning.
- Bunch of saps...
- Why are they saps?
- Let's not talk about the war.
You talk to Carlo.
Only saps risk their lives for strangers.
- That's Pop talking.
- You're right, that's Pop talking!
- They risk their lives for their country.
- Country isn't your blood.
- I don't feel that way.
- Then quit college and join the army!
I did.
I've enlisted in the Marines.
- Why didn't you come to us?
- What do you mean?
- Pop managed to get you a deferment.
- I didn't ask for it.
I didn't want it.
Come on! Knock it off!
- Punk!
- Sonny, sit down.
Mommy, Daddy's fighting again!
Go and show Carlo the tree.
Nice.
Break your father's heart
on his birthday.
That's swell, Mike. Congratulations.
Don't encourage him!
Get me a drink. Go on!
You don't understand.
Your father has plans for you.
Many times he and I have talked
about your future.
You've talked to my father
about my future?
- My future.
- Mikey, he has high hopes for you.
- I have my own plans for my future.
- Did you go to college to get stupid?
He's here!
Come on.
Stupid!
Surprise!
For he's a jolly good fellow
That nobody can deny
Nobody can deny...